Sam Nishanth Simson

Profession: Full Stack Developer.

Location: Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India.

E-Mail : <u>samnsimson@gmail.com</u>

Contact : +91 9487354083

Summary

An enthusiastic and competent Full Stack Developer offering over 1 year of IT expertise with excellent track record demonstrating solid design and problem solving skills covering a wide range of companies from small start-ups to large enterprise corporations. To begin my career at a highly-reputed and eminent organization and to gain exceptional career move ahead through long efforts and performance regularity. A position in Information Technology field providing the opportunity to make a strong contribution to organizational goals through continued development of professional skills.

Education

Anna University

Bachelor's Degree, B.E., Computer Science and Engineering, 2013 - 2017

Experience

Full Stack Developer - Doodleblue Innovations Pvt. Ltd

June 2017 - Present

Being a Full Stack Developer, Involvement in development of Front end, Back end, Mobile technologies and CMS was my core responsibilities in Doodleblue Innovations. Majority of my works are on PHP, Magento, WordPress and Angular JS.

Skils: PHP, Codeignighter, Magento, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS, Ionic framework, AWS

PHP Developer – IT Bay Inc.

January 2016 - April 2017

As a PHP Developer I was working to implement various components to extend functionality of Web applications, maintain and support existing functionality, design and implement new functionality

Skils: PHP, Codeignighter, JavaScript, Jquery, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS.

WordPress Developer – Flycart Technologies.

June 2016 – September 2016

As a PHP Developer I was working to implement various components to extend functionality of Web applications, maintain and support existing functionality, design and implement new functionality

Skils: PHP, Codeignighter, JavaScript, Jquery, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS.

Freelancing

As a Freelance Developer along with my development team has worked on client projects that includes development of static and dynamic large scale web application, development of mobile applications using cross platform technologies, testing and doing bug fixes on mobile applications and web applications.

Skils: PHP, WordPress, Magento, JavaScript, Jquery, REST API, MEAN stack, Node JS, Ionic Framework, Angular JS, MongoDB.

Languages

English (Read, Write, Speak), Tamil (Read, Write, Speak)

Skills & Expertise

- **Programming**: C, C++, Java
- Web Development: HTML5 & CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, PHP, Angular JS
- Mobile Development: Apache Cordova, Ionic Framework
- Database: MySQL, Firebase (NoSQL), MongoDB (NoSQL)
- CMS: WordPress, Magento, WooCommerce
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects
- **Frameworks**: Jquery Javascript, Codeignighter PHP, Ionic Mobile applications/Angular JS.

Projects

Industry web portal

Time duration: July - August 2016 (2 month)

As a freelancer this was my second project on PHP/HTML. having worked on the project for 2hrs/day it took 15 days to complete the development and updates and testing. I've used Bootstrap for the responsiveness of the site and kept the code re-usable and simple that the site loads in seconds. the mailing function has been implemented with php for contact form.

WordPress template development

Time duration: June - July 2016 (2 month)

As a PHP developer this was my 1st wordpress custom template development project. Having sound knowledge in PHP and MySQL database, I took interest in developing the template on my own. Wrote custom functions and hooks with PHP scripts in implementing the backend of the template. Wrote more than 1000+ lines of CSS styles that makes the template look classic and responsive. Usage of bootstrap framework made the template user friendly and responsive. With more than 10+ custom designed pages, this template is suitable for any browser and for different platforms.

Academy Website

Time duration: June 2016 (1 month)

As a freelancer this was my 1st wordpress project. Having taken the responsibility of building the site, I've gathered necessary requirement and details that the client needed on the site. I used custom CSS and Scripts that are needed to make the template come out as expected. I worked with plugins that enables functions like mailing, blogging, subscription and user management. Good and clear communication with the client helped me develop the site as per the requirement at a short span of time.

• Blood bank application - Android (Cross platform)

Time duration: September 2016 - November 2016

Blood bank application was a cross platform android application built using Ionic framework and with firebase backend support. Angular JS was the language that I've used to program the application. Firebase was used as database to store data. This application is compatible for any android OS with version 4.0 and higher.

E-commerce Application – Android (Cross platform)

Time duration: September 2016 - November 2016

This was my personal android project on E-Commerce application on Android. Being a cross platform application, I've used ionic framework and firebase to build the application. Angular JS was the language used for programming the application.

E-commerce Application – PHP & MySQL

Time duration: September 2016

My personal PHP project was this E-commerce application. Built over PHP and MySQL this application provides all the basic functionalities of an E-Commerce application along with an admin panel to add and manage products.

Certificates:

Freelancer contest winner

June 2016

Won the contest hosted on Freelancer.com graphic design contest.

• Computer Society of India – Student Convention

March 2016

Secured 1st position in Programming and designing contest.

Inter collegiate techno fest

February 2016

Positioned as one of the leading contestants in national appathon challenge.

National level Appathon

August 2015

Secured 3rd position in Web application development.

National level Coding Contest - SAMHITA

February 2015

Participated in national level coding contest.

Computer Society of India – Student Convention

December 2014

Secured 1st position in programming contest.

Project Reference:

- https://github.com/Sam1996/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-nishanth-60672a79/
- https://github.com/Sam1996/WordPress Template PHP/
- http://www.primedesignindia.com/
- http://www.carpediemskillsacademy.com/
- http://cheshireindia.org/
- http://www.regencypackaging.com/
- https://royalnautical.co.uk/

Extra-Curricula's

- Represented under 19 Divisional Cricket team
- Representing University Field Hockey Team.

.